<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Doris Zhou's Blog</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Doris Zhou's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 18:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reflection on the Attention Merchants</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 18:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reflection on the Attention Merchants" />&lt;p>Attention merchants are everywhere, dominating our lives. Here I am, starting my first unplugging ever. Social media, reality TV, and quick mobile game have been deterring me from focusing on my job and people around me. The habitual scrolling or the constant blaring of taboo-filled TV shows are indicators that I have been making a deal with the devil/attention merchants. I have never been one to have set a clear boundary between the internet and I. My friends know me to reply instantly and always be overshare my daily life on social media with no hesitation. This book The Attention Merchants has made me become more aware of how my attentions have been stolen and exchanged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book started with an introduction detailing a company named EFP that exchanged students’ attentions for funding for the school board. Essentially, the board entered the agreement to sell students’ attentions in exchange of free money, and corporations could then influence students’ awareness of the brands and establish life-long purchase habits. This real-life story reminds me of one episode of Daria, where the principal brought advertisements into the school for additional funding. The principal avoided scrutiny by hosting a community meeting during the Super Bowls. Even after Daria successfully exposed the principal for the reckless money grabber she was, we saw Daria and Jane walked out of the school building covered in Ultra Cola ads. Jane looked at Daria and declared success sarcastically since the ads could only be displayed outside of school. That storyline is incredibly similar to that of this book and every attention revolution. When a new form of attention merchants emerge, people usually are oblivious. Then they become outraged once these merchants’ evil practices have been exposed. Eventually, the attention merchants provide enough convenience for the users that people just sit there and accept them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After Wu painted this egregious picture of improper marketing practice, he introduced us to the first attention merchant. Benjamin Day, a print shop proprietor, decided to include advertising in newspapers to reduce cost. His newspaper, the &lt;em>New York Sun&lt;/em>, became the leading paper in a year solely relying on taboos and its low cost. His practice started a new category of news coverage that used attention grabbing as its main concern. In 1835, the Sun convinced most people that there were little creatures on the moon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/rishabh-sharma-R-js25Pv1LQ-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="960"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/rishabh-sharma-R-js25Pv1LQ-unsplash_hufd084b624d2d50cb9d07454e9b289e46_251445_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/rishabh-sharma-R-js25Pv1LQ-unsplash_hufd084b624d2d50cb9d07454e9b289e46_251445_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Rishabh Sharma on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu then introduced the first cultural revolt against the attention merchants. The invention of Jule Chéret , the advertising posters, took over the streets of Paris and started to become an assault on everyone’s eyeballs. This intrusion of attention harvesting eventually led to the anti-poster movement and limited the poster spread. There was something deeper behind simply aesthetic concerns. The awareness of one’s attention being exchanged for financial gains without one’s consent is the ultimate insult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The industry that became the likely representation of attention merchants turned out to be patent medicine, any sorts of natural healing products that provided nothing of scientific evidence. Claude Hopkins led the campaign to oversell these products and bring the manufacturer a large sum of money, while the actual ingredients of these products had no real medical benefits and were actually toxic. When you find pamphlets from random stores in your mailbox, you have Hopkins to thank! He invented “direct mailing”. When the patent medicine empire of Hopkins was just starting to grow, Samuel Adams, a former crime reporter, exposed the truth behind these products. To the consumer’s shock, some products contained sulphuric acid and the lab testing on animals had led to fatality. FDA was established as a result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu then described the marketing strategies used by royalty. During the First World War, Lord Kitchener recruited soldiers and inspired the iconic “Uncle Sam”. His fingers pointed to whoever was reading the poster with the caption “Your country needs YOU”. The British invented the war propaganda and would subsequently become the inspiration of the Soviet Union, communist China, and Nazi Germany. America was the next to follow in the political propaganda. George Creel, an assistant to Woodrow Wilson’s campaign, convinced the Americans that going to war was the patriotic choice and spread nationalist propaganda. The ordinary people were giving pro-war speeches, and propaganda films were produced. Uncle Sam came out during this time as well. People who were anti-war were arrested under the Espionage Act. The propaganda of the British and American filled some journalists with dismay, but some paid attention to the effectiveness of total government campaigns. Among those was Hitler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu introduced Scientific Advertising, a term included demand engineering, branding, and targeted advertisements. This scientific approach took over the advertising world. The predominant figure in this era was surprisingly once again Hopkins, who came out of his retirement. Products now utilized fear campaign, Freud’s unconsciousness, and results of different experiments. Brands now were associated with more than products, but an identity. Soon after, the men in advertising realized that women were often the missing targets of the market. Helen Landsowne, a female advertiser, used the common desire of women to be beautiful and implied that a product had the potential to lead to a better life. In the meantime, some products used fear to create market demands, some products associated themselves with political movements and traits consumers identified with, and some products used Celebrity endorsement as a new force in advertising. During this era, advertiser became smarter and sneakier, using a wide range of tools to capture attention of those who were missed with the initial strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alicia-christin-gerald-zm4CcBeBbp8-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="427"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alicia-christin-gerald-zm4CcBeBbp8-unsplash_hu6e62c94063290f450253decd7f8f55a3_34989_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alicia-christin-gerald-zm4CcBeBbp8-unsplash_hu6e62c94063290f450253decd7f8f55a3_34989_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Alicia Christin Gerald on Unsplash "
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="149"
data-flex-basis="359px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu then illustrated the stories of the &lt;em>Lucky Strike&lt;/em>. The success of its branding started with the false claim of the health benefits of &lt;em>Lucky strike&lt;/em> cigarettes and the “toasting” process. The classic doctor endorsement appeared in their advertisement. To get women to smoke, they framed smoking as an act of feminist freedom and acclaimed smoking as a weight-loss treatment. Quite despicable, but it worked wonders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon came the consumer movement, incited by the manifesto &lt;em>Your Money’s Worth&lt;/em>. Many former copywriters described the evil practices of advertising after the exposé. Along with the financial burdens caused by the Depression, Americans became angry towards the attention merchants. Advertisement should distribute information for the consumers, but based on these articles, these attention merchants had disobeyed the rule of the free market. An economist, Edward Chamberlin, criticized brand loyalty. As a result, FTC regained its power and oversaw advertising practices. The attention merchants, though weakened, had not had their last laughs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu started the next chapter, introducing the radio. Radio advertising had emerged as a new form of attention capturing technique. The hit radio show &lt;em>Amos n Andy&lt;/em> became the first prime-time show, with Pepsodent, a failing toothpaste company, as the sponsor. As the show became the most popular show, even to this day, NBC learned that they can “sell eyeballs”, Pepsodent’s sale increased more than two folds, and an industry found out that they could own a part of the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To compete with NBC, The CBS president, Paley decided CBS would provide content for free in exchange for sponsored content. Paley discovered Orson Welles and other talents, but he also remembered to set a limit on its advertising to keep CBS interesting and critics-free. CBS was also the first network to hire its own reporters. To prove to sponsors that their generosity had indeed made a difference in their sales, the &lt;em>Audimeter&lt;/em>, the early form of the Nielson box, was invented.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alberto-bobbera-EFhMssXvxeU-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="958"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alberto-bobbera-EFhMssXvxeU-unsplash_hu3a0011fe8afbc3a25e92ce8352db3128_73831_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/alberto-bobbera-EFhMssXvxeU-unsplash_hu3a0011fe8afbc3a25e92ce8352db3128_73831_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Alberto Bobbera on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, the time has come to talk about one of the most predominant and notorious attention merchants. Adolf Hitler reintroduced the standing German army after the last notes of Beethoven’s Symphony. Hitler learned from the best: the British propaganda in the First World War. He understood the only way to break the German’s objectivity was to tend to the less educated masses. As a former ads man, he suggested that propaganda had an important goal to attract attention. To suit the message to the “the great mass”, the message must be simple and resolved to slogans and small words. He knew emotions were more welcomed than persuasion, and crowd psychology moved even those who were intelligent. Other than the fact that he was already naturally blessed with an enunciation and charisma beyond any men, the radio played a crucial role in Hitler’s domination. The propaganda took over all air time as the more German started to listen to the radio. Opposed to the advertisers, instead of informing people of their choices, Hitler took away people’s freedom to observe other opinions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the war ended, televisions took over America by storm. &lt;em>I love Lucy&lt;/em> and &lt;em>The Ed Sullivan Show&lt;/em> took CBS over the edge. TV advertisement was the next to follow, with Kellogg, Cadillac, Marlboro leading the trend. Warm association added an extra layer of attraction for company branding. Soon, 6he Competition between NBC and CBS brought quiz shows to drew audiences. Attention merchants like pain relievers and Crest did not miss the advertising break during these attention-grabbing shows to demonstrate their brand superiority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this time of TV show prosperity came a second attention revolt. This time around, it was the invention of remote controls. Remote controls gave the audience the freedom to move their attention away from the ads and to freely choose something more entertaining. Ads were revealed to be extremely effective when it came to attention manipulation, and game shows were exposed to be staged for dramatic effects. These scandals eventually led to the 60s attention revolt. Timothy Leary, a former Harvard professor, led the Great Refusal by following the most revolutionary American slogans and invented “Turn on, Tune in, Drop out”. To his surprise, as he appropriated the advertisers’ tactics, the advertisers similarly used his cause for their purpose. Pepsi, hoping to end their underdog journey, identified themselves with the attention revolt. They became the representation of youth, individualism, and anti-establishment. Against Coke’s all-American brand association, Pepsi started to close the gap slowly. During the same era, the attention merchants turned themselves to the children. Mr. Rogers, Sesame Street, and Charlie Brown captured Children’s attention. New advertisers associated brands with social issues that were the centre of conversations such as the second-wave feminism. Unfortunately for the resistance, capitalism had and continued to be known to be resilient and adaptable. Capitalism in the 70s wrote individualism and freedom into its playbook, continuing to deny a simple way of living to Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To distribute advertisements more efficiently, a former New York University professor, Robbin, developed computer models PRIZM (Potential Ratings in ZIP Markets) and sorted the US into clusters with different shopping habits and living conditions. Based on the cluster a household is in, advertisers sent out pamphlets and produced billboards based on their profiles. Cable networks targeting each cluster started to pop out, ESPN, BET, and Bravo. Fox News also started as a target network for conservative viewers. With the increasing numbers of TV channels, channel surfing had emerged as an unintended consequence, producing inattentive scattered viewers. Commercials learned about celebrity endorsement. Super Bowl became a spectacle. The great refusal ended with a whimper, leading to a more capable and effective attention economy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Wu covered the appearance of the third screen - the computer screen. The email was invented and saved the internet from a premature death. The check-in ritual, habitual checking of your digital mailbox to see if there was any new email, would eventually become the mode of attention capturing for all social media. The first spam mail was a several-page long invitation to an event. Though even the Pentagon was furious with the spam mail, trolling and spamming never truly stopped after that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="427"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash_hu08e4dcda6fff2f9b9b3294828bf7f8d2_25040_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash_hu08e4dcda6fff2f9b9b3294828bf7f8d2_25040_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Cookie the Pom on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="149"
data-flex-basis="359px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The potential of computer for personal entertainment was soon discovered. The arcade game &lt;em>Space Invaders&lt;/em> took over the world by storm. A new model, cash for experience, was invented. The urge to complete against others made the game an addiction. To win over women and girls, &lt;em>Pac-Man&lt;/em> then became a social craze. To encourage more casual use of the internet, four companies competed for dominance in the computer network. These subscription based services offered access to then-government-owned internet with a small selection of online spaces. AOL used communities to entertain themselves. Despite the lack of funding compared to all other companies, AOL came up with a strategy, to make its space happy and friendly. It’s infamous chat rooms allowed private rooms, which eventually evolved into sex-related flirtation. Prodigy, one of the other companies, implemented a profanity ban in its chat rooms as they tried to keep the chat rooms pristine. The Draconian method to online speech eventually attracted more users to AOL. With 4 million users, AOL came out in front. To continue its growth, AOL offered advertisement rights to companies. These companies engaged in bidding wars to be able to advertise their products in AOL. The dawn of the internet started as an intense war zone, but the competition certainly did not stop here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the Internet was still in its cradle stage, the entertainment industry was evolving in the speed of lightening. Celebrity power was harnessed to strengthen attention merchants’ hold on the mass. &lt;em>Times&lt;/em> and &lt;em>People&lt;/em> filled their pages with celebrity gossips and personality stories. For any platform invented after, celebrities became the attention merchants’ first bait, luring people in. For example, the celebrity-focused television,
Oprah’s show became a huge success through combining entertainment with her supportive discussion, the fascinating cuisine, and her spiritual/religious objectives. Even with more competition, Oprah stayed on top. Her personal growth theory encouraged consumption, and a single sentence of endorsement booked $90,000 in a single afternoon. The Oprah empire was soon established from the audiences&amp;rsquo; frenzy. Though eventually the rating of her show dropped due to her endorsement of the law of attraction, and her TV channel drowned into the hundreds of channels now on TV, her rise to fame did inspire many other shows like Ellen DeGeneres, Dr. Phil, Rachael Ray, and other product endorsement focused celebrity shows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reality TV was soon invented by MTV. Despite the initial backlash, reality shows proved themselves to be cheaper to produce and sometimes more attention capturing compared to TV shows. Reality TV shows appealed to the mass and promised celebrity and fame to the ordinary people. This promise produced a sustainable economy similar to the capitalism‘a promise of richness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the internet finally became a free and unlimited space for everyone to enjoy, Google, with its clean algorithms and limited ads interface, started to attract users. To sustain its growth, instead of delivering ads that were purely distracting, Google designed targeted ads that added values to the customer’s experience. Using AdWords (now known as Google Ads), Google became the most profitable attention merchant. Blogging became a trend among internet users. The sharing of a blog became a new way to harvest attention. YouTube as a form of self-expression attracted amateurs, professionals, and commercial content. The Huffington Post was established as a prime utiliser of the clickbait.
Young Mark Zuckerberg invented Facebook with his determination to prove that he was the better developer. Turned out that people loved sharing personal details and experience online. It surpassed MySpace because of its control of page design and proper control of certain content. It took over the social media world because of its stability and usability. Though Facebook could not conveniently insert ads like Google, it eventually found other ways to demonstrate its advertising value. Its like buttons tracked people’s preference so appropriate ads could be shown to its users. The beauty of social media proved to be attractive in a Skinneresque manner. Though most content was disappointing, the occasional rewards kept people coming back for more. At the same time, Twitter provided a platform for everyone to share their everyday thoughts casually. The invention of followers conveniently pushed interesting content to everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/prateek-katyal-xv7-GlvBLFw-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="427"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/prateek-katyal-xv7-GlvBLFw-unsplash_hua7a0fa5382ba16a3a2905f74835861cf_17574_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/reflection-attention-merchants/prateek-katyal-xv7-GlvBLFw-unsplash_hua7a0fa5382ba16a3a2905f74835861cf_17574_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Prateek Katyal on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="149"
data-flex-basis="359px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the competition among social media sites were heating up, phone arrived as the fourth screen thanks to the Canadian company BlackBerry. While different mobile games were trending, Instagram appeared as a picture-centric social media application. Successful attention merchants like the Kardashian utilized this new media to resell attention and amounted to millions of dollars.&lt;br>
Netflix became a successful attention merchant without an ad-centric approach. The word “binge-watching” was included in the dictionary thanks to Netflix’s rise to popularity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the other tech companies indulged in attention resale and privacy erosion. Apple decided that they would choose privacy of their customers as their priorities. Apple implemented tracker and ads blockers, infuriated attention merchants like Mark Zuckerberg. This act of privacy protection also put Android in peril, since Google had chosen the attention model of operation, making it difficult for Android to come out on top.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wu concluded that we may never fully get rid of attention merchants. Ultimately, advertisements served as informative tools for the consumers. Yet, there had been too little regulations imposed on how intrusive these attention merchants could be. With the convenience and entertain under our fingertips, we, in exchange, had our privacy eroded by attention merchants. These attention merchants are intruders in our daily lives. Without our consent, these merchants took away our privacy and occupied our freedom in exchange for free or cheap entertainment. Wu encouraged us to reclaim our time and emphasized the damage it may have on society if most of our attention was spent unfocused and scattered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His call to action did give me the idea for starting the unplugging. The book comprehensively described the evolution of attention merchants and highlighted different strategies to capture attention. We have long been warned that social media like Instagram and Facebook have negative effects on our mental health. Companies use ads to create unnecessary demands and use social issues to raise brand awareness. We are constantly distracted by different attention merchants craving for our attentions. Short videos on popular platforms like TikTok and Instagram reduced our attention span to quick burst of interesting moments. With the rising popularity of different streaming platform, we no longer carefully analyze the shows we watch. Instead, we binge through multiple shows a week. Crazy enough, some platforms invite us to watch shows with two times the speed. Everything in our life exist with the secondary purpose to resell our attention. Research in computer science and data science is focusing on distributing ads more efficiently. The world exists in serving the capitalist purpose to gain more profits for the attention merchants. I miss the days before the internet and phones, when we spent time outdoors and read a lot more. I miss the days before social media commercialization where we simply went online for socialization and not scrolling through pages of advertisements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to live like that again, authentic and pure, stress-free yet purposeful. Even if I do wish to exchange my attention for entertainment or convenience, it better be a thoughtful and relaxing experience with my full consent, rather than the 50-page privacy agreement the companies are pushing onto us. It is the time to call for another attention revolt, even if it’s one that only involves one person, you. I refuse to let attention merchants occupy my thoughts. My thoughts that are better spent on the real, touchable beauty in the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cats I Met in Toronto Cat Rescue</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 17:35:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Cats I Met in Toronto Cat Rescue" />&lt;p>This post is dedicated to those beautiful feline friends I encountered while volunteering for Toronto Cat Rescue. In a tiny room, less than 5 square meters, we shared bonds that could not be understated by the limited time we spent together. These are cats who were born into misery, whose mom was abandoned, who had gone through drastic changes in their lives, or whose existence had been doomed. Yet through these difficult circumstances, they became the most resilient, the sweetest, and the most hopeful creatures I had ever seen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cookie">Cookie&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2_hu387499013c52eee6399ada8520b583a6_27029_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/cookie-2_hu387499013c52eee6399ada8520b583a6_27029_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Cookie"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cookie was cuddly. He loved to eat and begged for treats. He was gorgeous.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sensei">Sensei&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei_huec0609375015a401b4499d9fc65f1fb5_29057_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/sensei_huec0609375015a401b4499d9fc65f1fb5_29057_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sensei"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sensei came with her kittens, who were named after the teenage ninja turtles. She was still nursing. An adventurous little one. She was always leading the whole family to escape the tiny adoption centre. She was beautiful and cuddly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="april-and-rafael">April and Rafael&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael_hu0399c61e3307fe4babd12f6a612346e9_23794_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/april-rafael_hu0399c61e3307fe4babd12f6a612346e9_23794_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Rafael (On the left) and April (On the right)"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>April and Rafael were troublemakers who were always wrestling. Rafael had a bad case of biting people for fun. April licked you when you tried to engage in kitten fighting behaviours.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="four-calioco-sisters">Four calioco sisters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha.jpg"
width="300"
height="400"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha_hu13691b4b0f867829e331154d937f205a_23807_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/harsha_hu13691b4b0f867829e331154d937f205a_23807_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Harsh, one of the calico sisters"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The four gorgeous girls were all diluted calico. Two of them were shy and reserved, while their sisters roamed around the centre. Their mom hated the new environment. Four girls got adopted pretty fast. I did fall in love with one of them, a shy little one named Adi. She was too shy to come and snuggle in any way, but her gorgeous and timid eyes were locked on me. She would stand on the edge of the cage, trying to gather the courage to reach out to me. That was the closest I’ve come to almost adopting another cat.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gerrard">Gerrard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard.jpg"
width="300"
height="533"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard_hu8b198ca585a95eb973522b69267ef98a_25282_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/gerrard_hu8b198ca585a95eb973522b69267ef98a_25282_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Gerrad"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="56"
data-flex-basis="135px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gerrard was a loud little guy. His meowing could be heard from across PetSmart. He left on the day I met him to a gorgeous family. He would have a good life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="padou">Padou&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou.jpg"
width="300"
height="400"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou_hu962327032267833dcc5eea9f03bbc1f3_24757_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/padou_hu962327032267833dcc5eea9f03bbc1f3_24757_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Padou"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="75"
data-flex-basis="180px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Padou, a French princess. From the limited interaction I had with her, she craved physical touch. She rubbed her head on mine against the cage.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="charlie">Charlie&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie.jpg"
width="300"
height="549"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie_hu12895b3d126910a401a3a3f0af0bf511_29714_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/cat-tcr/charlie_hu12895b3d126910a401a3a3f0af0bf511_29714_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Charlie"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="54"
data-flex-basis="131px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Charlie was one of the sweetest boys I’ve ever met. He rubbed up on my legs with the force I’ve rarely encountered. He loved sitting on my laps and the tilapia breakfast. He stared at every shopper who stopped by the adoption centre, hoping they would be the one that took him home. Thank god, he got adopted after a week at the adoption centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Jae Park&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Unsplash&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Doomsday</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/doomsday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 21:43:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/doomsday/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/doomsday/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Doomsday" />&lt;p>Sea level rising&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forests burning&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stock market screaming the prelude to doomsday&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are holding my hand&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the darkness of the starless sky of Toronto&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With cars zooming by&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Leaving trails of light pollution&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The car still smells of&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lust desire and intimacy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are sparkles and dreams in your eyes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That I am planting&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Along with those kisses&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guns blazing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Protests raging&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Warships lining up the dazzling reflection of explosions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your lips are on mine&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The perfect day to&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let the fire swallow us whole&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Photo by &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/@christopher__burns?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Christopher Burns&lt;/a> on &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/fire?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Unsplash&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Mission</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/mission/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Mission" />&lt;h2 id="5-days-till-the-mission">5 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Her laptop displays the elegant page of a jewelry store that centers on a pair of simmering gold earrings. In the note section, a short sentence reads &amp;ldquo;9-inch chain, one bracelet, one earring - Amy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She quickly closes the laptop when her son comes in. His adolescent sweat stinks up half the room. She tightens her brows, &amp;ldquo;Take a shower.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A recording pops up on her phone for review. She has done this plenty of times. It’s amusing how much more you start to learn once you have joined the force. On the recording, a young woman, presumably Amy, whispers to the microphone, confirming the order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flowers in her yard are blooming gorgeously on this early summer day. The neighbour waves at her when she comes out to collect the mail. Her phone buzzes. Two addresses pop up in the text preview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beauty of the organization is that almost everything is autonomous and anonymous. No one in the organization has access to the information of a pickup, drop-off, or host family. She doesn’t know who started the organization or even who is in the organization besides the handful of host families she has personally met. No one but the algorithm knows that she will have to be at this first address in 5 days, pick up some scared young woman named Amy, and drop her off at the second address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her hands sweat profusely when the thought of the mission pops up in her head. She drops her phone by accident. Her neighbour smiles, and she shrugs. Three mindless chatters and a half later, she closes the door.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-days-till-the-mission">4 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fifteen years ago, she was in a similar situation. Teenage and pregnant. She wore the baggy hoodie on top of her fragile little body in and out of the rundown apartment to hide the increasingly noticeable baby bump and the bruises. The baby’s father was ten years her senior, with the smell of lcohol on his breath and clumsy body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She had nobody after her mother passed away. The world was closing in on her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She usually barely conversed with anybody except the shopkeep while shopping for groceries. One day, the sweet and gentle old lady who always browsed magazines at the bodega stopped her. She was flustered, but the old lady had a voice serene like a jar of marmalade. “Are you in some kind of trouble, sweetheart?” She remembered what the old lady said. She rushed home, hands shivering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since that night, every time she went to the bodega, she would be stopped by the old lady for a small chat. Her baby bump started to protrude from even her baggiest hoodie. The man at home was still merciless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, she told the old lady everything. She remembered they hid under the hood of the tiny bodega while the falling rain poured, the old lady’s wrinkled hand on her recovering bruises.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A month later, closer to the baby’s due date, while the man was snoring after yet another drunken rage, she took everything she owned. She took the leap of faith and got into that white sedan with the hazard light blinking in the middle of the night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She decides to drive to the first address after work to familiarize herself with the area. The address is near a park in the middle of the city. Nearby some kids are screaming in glee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She steps out of the car to explore the area. The sky is sapphire blue. She wonders how close this place is to Amy’s house. Her mind wanders back to the shabby apartment with the rusted fire exit. She wonders if Amy is as tiny and clueless as she was, staring out of the window, counting the seconds till the escape. She even wonders if any of the accompanying women in the park is indeed Amy, putting on a fake smile with strenuous effort, pulling up her top to hide any evidence of dismay.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-days-till-the-mission">3 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Her son is sick today. He locks himself up in the basement. She can hear his loud voice leak through the basement door while squandering another day playing video games. She sighs while putting the coffee cups away and drives off to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She still remembers how hard the pregnancy was. She spent a lot of time going in and out of the doctor’s office. She remembers the stern face of the doctor while explaining that the lack of nutrition throughout the first half of her pregnancy may lead to some health concerns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The host family offered to pay for supplements and bought baby clothes and toys. She cooked and cleaned even though the host family insisted on her resting most of the day. For the rest of the days, she hid in the house, refusing to expose to sunlight. She spent the next five years looking over her shoulder and waking up in the middle of the night in cold sweats. She saw herself a thousand times back in the suffocating room with the man’s snoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the baby turned one, she decided to move out of the host family. She never had a job, nor did she have anybody. The welfare cheque the host family helped her sign up for was abysmal. She had to get a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her elderly neighbour watched the baby for most days while she ran around the neighbourhood looking for minimum wage jobs. The thrifted blouse had lost its original colour and barely fit her body. She had never had a job nor made a cent on her own. So when the first paycheque arrived, she cried.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She arrives at her office. She is an accountant working for a mid-level corporation. The water cooler talks are bland and repetitive, but she feels blessed listening to Debbie complaining about her 20-year-old daughter. She calls her son around noon and remind him of the pasta she left in the fridge. He frequently goes all day without eating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He has asked her about his father before, but she tells him that she will tell him more once he turns 18. When he was younger, he would always get upset about not having a father. She did all she could to provide for him and comfort him. He is now a respectful teenager with an appropriate amount of pent-up anger and brainless behaviours. He has adjusted well to the world though the first couple of years of his existence was chaotic and brutal. Last year on Mother’s Day, he bought her a bouquet with his lousy handwriting. She still keeps the card in her drawer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-days-till-the-mission">2 days till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The city starts to pour. The drive back home is wet and blurry. She turns off the radio and sits in silence for a bit. The phone vibrates. It’s a reminder of the mission. “A delivery is scheduled for 2:30 am.” The coldness of the message feels almost industrial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The truth is hidden under the glittery cover of a jewelry delivery.
She got involved with the organization by accident. One of her close friends familiar with her experience confided in her and told her about the organization. Over the alcohol scent of the late-night cocktail, she decided to apply through the website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this enormous and mysterious web of men and women, who believe in rescuing women in abusive relationships who cannot escape through their means, comes together in this organization, anonymously hoping to save one life at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Someone experiencing domestic violence can choose to purchase a 9-inch chain, one bracelet, and one earring. It stands for 911. The system will first confirm the order or that there is indeed a woman in need by calling the number provided. The confirmation will be replayed to multiple participants of the transfers to ensure authenticity. Then the system automatically schedules a series of transfers to avoid having the victim being tracked by the abuser. A woman in need may go through 3 to 5 host families before settling down in one family. Another transfer may be scheduled anytime if the woman feels like their safety is compromised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She didn’t have such an organized support system back in the day. The driver who picked her up was the son of the elderly lady, and the host family was his friend’s. They did the best they could with the limited recourses, but she has always been grateful. These people who were strangers risked their safety and sacrificed their security to protect a woman whom they barely knew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though the host family is more than 100 miles away from where she used to live, she spent most of her first year tiptoeing around the world outside of her basement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She remembers the day when a familiar face popped up near her host family during her walk with her son. One of his friends was in fishing attire, wandering around the street. The small-town summer attracted a lot of people from the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She panicked, dragging the stroller down the street. The horror was indescribable. Suddenly, she was once again sitting quietly in that smoke-filled room, not daring to make a single sound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She ran and ran and ran. The stroller slowed her down. She couldn’t remember how many people she ran into or how long she was running. She stopped at the back of a construction site with sweat dripping down her face. Inside the stroller, her son was crying hysterically. A construction worker walked past her, “Ma’am, are you alright?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day she started to pack up. Within a week, she stepped onto the platform of a train south.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The map on her car GPS slowly turns from red to yellow. The traffic in front of her starts to dissipate. She puts down her phone and brings her thoughts back to reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-day-till-the-mission">1 day till the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thunders once again surround the city. After cooking dinner, she feels a bit nervous about the pickup tomorrow. It is not her first time, but she understands the risk never diminishes no matter how experienced she becomes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow is the day. She clenches her fist. Her son is quietly on his phone at the kitchen table. His rare presence at the dinner table is amusing. She raises her eyebrows and asks what the special occasion is. He shrugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nobody knows that she is a part of the organization, not even the friend who initially introduced her to it. It is one of the rules to keep each mission as secretive as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After dinner, she leaves to top up gas. While she is pumping gas, a man comes up to her and asks for direction. She suspiciously answers with a brief description. Doesn’t everyone have a google map on their phone these days?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, he asks, “May I have your number?” She politely rejects while stating that she has a boyfriend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, that statement is a lie. She has barely dated since the escape over a decade ago. Besides the stress of being a single mother, she has trouble navigating through the dating world. Her brief period of therapy has been cut short due to the lack of money and time. She hasn’t had a chance to fully isolate herself from the nightmares that still revisit her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While studying accounting, she did meet a gentle young man at school. She was working and studying full time, leaving her son all day with the babysitter and the neighbour. He would come over after school and before the end of her shift and look after her son.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her son enjoyed every second of his company. They would play soccer in the park next to her apartment. On the weekend, he took him to bbq while she spent all day cleaning. So when he decided to end the relationship, her son was devastated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things went downhill once the conversation on next steps started to come up. He was eager to push the relationship to the next level, while she refused to rush into anything. Suddenly, the only father figure her son had ever had exited out of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She was called to school to pick up her misbehaving son after he got into a fight. The sun was shining down brightly on the dusty park swings. She sat next to him with the clenched fists and tears running down his bloody nose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that relationship, she’s been more careful with letting her guards down with anyone new. The next thing she knows, she is approaching her 40s, her son is almost an adult, and she is still alone and fragile in the world, scared to commit. How can she risk another incident that can lead to another devastation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She pulls up in her driveway. The LED light in her son’s bedroom is changing colour gradually. Tomorrow is the day. She is ready, yet when is she really ready?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-day-of-the-mission">The day of the mission&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>She tiptoes downstairs. The moonlight spills all over the front of her front yard like milk. Cicadas sang vibrantly. She gets in her car. The sound of the engine floods her ears. She takes a deep breath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the designated spot, she parks her car and sits in complete darkness. She has to wait 30 minutes before aborting the pickup. She looks around the area. It’s 2:30 am. Every house on the street is sleeping on this peaceful night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suddenly, a tiny shadow on the corner scratches and breaks the silence of the night. A young girl appears under the street light. The girl is dragging a large duffel bag while wearing a baggy T-shirt, looking fragile and scared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She turns on her hazard lights. The girl’s eyes brighten up. The girl walks a little faster now, but the bag slows her down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She comes out and walks out of the car. “This is for the jewelry delivery?” The girl nods timidly and fixes the collar of her T-shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They drive off. She looks at the girl in the trunk. The girl, presumably Amy, is looking out the window nervously with her hands awkwardly placed on her tiny thighs. She hears Amy’s little voice in the back of the car, &amp;ldquo;Thank you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They arrive at the drop-off location. She opens the trunk and takes out Amy&amp;rsquo;s duffle bag. She turns around, and Amy is standing next to the car door with tears all over her face. &amp;ldquo;I am scared.&amp;rdquo; Amy can barely mutter a complete sentence, &amp;quot; I have never been alone before. I don’t know if I can make it&amp;hellip; I don’t know how to survive on my own&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She cuts her off sternly, &amp;ldquo;You will make it! You have to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She takes Amy’s hands in hers. She sees her younger teenage self in Amy’s sniffling. &amp;ldquo;You’re stronger than you can ever imagine. You have to believe it. Today will be the beginning of the toughest battle you’ll ever face, but you will make it. You have to tell yourself that. Now, go on and ring the doorbell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amy looks down for a minute and then nods. She watches Amy dragging the oversized duffle bag to the front door and ringing the doorbell. Someone comes out, confirms the details, and takes Amy in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She stands in the walkway that is blossoming with tulips. It’s a beautiful summer night. Another girl’s life is forever changed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflection on "Capitalist Realism"</title><link>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 16:56:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reflection on "Capitalist Realism"" />&lt;p>As a Bernie bro turned half-closeted anti-capitalist, I am slightly embarrassed to admit that this book is the first book I’ve read that goes in-depth explaining capitalism. Life in engineering has completely devoid me of any free time to sit down and read. This free time after graduation becomes the first time in a long while that I could indulge my curiosity about late-term capitalism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fisher started the book with the description of a vital scene in the movie &lt;em>Children of Men&lt;/em>. He then brought up the phrase:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is easier to imagine the end of the world than it is to imagine the end of capitalism.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In two pages, Fisher immediately captured the reader. It is undeniably true that often time in any discussion regarding anti-capitalism, a common response from the opposer is usually that though capitalism is evil, there is simply no other viable political and economical system. Thus, capitalist realism: the belief that capitalism is “real” and the only plausible social system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fisher then dived into a discussion about arts in the modern days and explained how hip-hop has gained increasing popularity. Fisher explained postmodernism briefly and pointed out that the current over-saturation of media is largely a phenomenon of late-capitalism: once a certain story/style has gained considerable popularity, artists/producers are reluctant to produce anything new. They reproduce the same storylines or music (if it ain’t broke and brings in profit, why fix it?). A prime example of this is the number of box office movies that fall into the “remake” genre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/jp-valery-blOLCO2K4M0-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="960"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/jp-valery-blOLCO2K4M0-unsplash_hu874f7db50861200958d60722f107e63b_41325_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/jp-valery-blOLCO2K4M0-unsplash_hu874f7db50861200958d60722f107e63b_41325_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Jp Valery on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="66"
data-flex-basis="160px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next couple of chapters, Fisher declared that moral criticism of capitalism only reinforces capitalist realism. This discussion reminds me of what Jeremiah Whitewhale said in the TV show &lt;em>Bojack Horseman&lt;/em>, after Diane confronted him on his evil anti-labour practice. He claimed that when news about his company evil practices come out, people think the company is uncompromised by morality, the stock goes up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the stranglehold capitalist realism has exacted on most people, Fisher illuminated that the only way to dismantle capitalist realism is to point out the inconsistencies within the capitalist ideals. Besides the already contested climate change issue, Fisher emphasized two other areas of discussion - mental health and bureaucracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next chapter, Fisher discussed reflexive impotence and depressive hedonia. He had an intriguing proposition that the individualization of mental health problems - “treating them as if they were caused by chemical imbalances in the individual’s neurology and/or by their family background“ - took out the possibility of societal causation. He then explained depressive hedonia: the phenomenon where depression is the result of the constant craving for pleasure. I am by no means an expert in depression or any other mental illness, but I am reluctant to agree that what gives rise to depression is a societal one and not a chemical one. I would be more inclined to accept this proposition if there is more evidence that there is more than a correlation between mental health issues and the over-saturation of media. Though it is evident that the number of people with diagnosed mental health issue skyrocketed in the last decade, based on a press release by American Psychological Association (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2019/03/mental-health-adults" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Mental Health Issues Increased Significantly in Young Adults Over Last Decade&lt;/a>), I attribute some of these effects to the developing and more comprehensive mental health support nowadays. These doubts aside, teens’ constant obsession over the “matrix” - as Fisher named the social media - harms their mental health. (&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.statista.com/topics/9178/social-media-and-teenage-mental-health/#dossierKeyfigures" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Social media and teenage mental health - Statistics and Facts&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Post-Fordism and the instability of the current workplace culture leak through workers’ workplaces and into their everyday lives. Due to the insepration between life and work, more workers suffer from mental distress. Without the assurance of job security, people are suffering from increasing stress. Yet, Fisher reminds us that capitalism denies any societal effects that may have led to this mental health endemic. At the same time, an abundance of wealth has been made by the pharmaceutical companies in the treatment of mental illness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/denys-nevozhai-eDPgef3PQ7U-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="425"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/denys-nevozhai-eDPgef3PQ7U-unsplash_hu5897b49702bbb776e03d7655132f89a7_86153_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/denys-nevozhai-eDPgef3PQ7U-unsplash_hu5897b49702bbb776e03d7655132f89a7_86153_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Denys Nevozhai on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="361px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next chapter, Fisher discussed the bureaucracy stemming from capitalism. Though theoritically capitalism aims to eliminate the bureaucracy in Stalinism by making all processes transactional, bureaucracy exists in capitalism more consistently and less tangibly. For example, there is no formal review in the workplace, but many employees are asked to set goals and self-reflect. The phrase “work smarter, not harder” emphasizes the need for change and puts immense pressure on the employees to adapt to the ever-changing labour market. I have always demised when companies ask for employees with multi-skills while offering salaries that one can barely scrape by. The obnoxious discussion of “lifelong learning” and “key-shaped person” implies that to be successful, one must be ready to constantly adapt to new challenges and reshape oneself. This implication is an unfair request from the capitalist society to employees while not providing any security and stability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beyond the inconsistencies of mental health and bureaucracy in capitalism, Fisher expresses his belief that capitalist realism is a merely plastic reality that is reconfiguring itself constantly. Capitalism urges people to adapt to changes with ease. The strongest survivors of the capitalist society believe that nothing is constant but change. Due to the lack of a central exchange in a capitalist society, people largely overlook the capital or big corporations as the culprits for large-scale societal problems. For example, people largely blame the government for the 2008 financial crisis while the behaviour of capital plays an essential role. Capitalism tends to resolve problems by making them everyone&amp;rsquo;s problems. Fisher used recycling as an example. The responsibilization results in no one really taking care of the problem. I have always been angry at politicians who deflected by claiming battling climate change is everyone&amp;rsquo;s responsibility. These very same politicians have been accepting donations from big oil companies and caressed by climate change denying lobbiests. Despicable of them to shame us for driving to work/school under the underfunded public infratstructure, while allowing the large carbon producers roam free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/marek-piwnicki-WiZOyYqzUss-unsplash.jpg"
width="640"
height="400"
srcset="https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/marek-piwnicki-WiZOyYqzUss-unsplash_huaeaedbcb0fe25a4e5a0485f02f737a17_28813_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://zhoudoris13.github.io/p/capitalist-realism/marek-piwnicki-WiZOyYqzUss-unsplash_huaeaedbcb0fe25a4e5a0485f02f737a17_28813_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Photo by Marek Piwnicki on Unsplash"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="160"
data-flex-basis="384px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fisher ended the book with the forewarning that late-term capitalism may divert to social democracy or authoritarianism. He warned that any effective anti-capitalist social system must be a rival to capitalism and not a reaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I genuinely enjoyed this book. This book is one of the first pieces of literature I have touched on in a few years, and it resonated with a lot of my frustrations. As a newbie in the anti-capitalist world, this book is a fantastic introduction to and an engaging discussion of many facets of late-term capitalism. There are a lot of &amp;ldquo;Ah-ha&amp;rdquo; moments in this book, such as the phenomena of postmodernism, the instability in the post-Fordism era, the omnipresence of bureaucracy in the workplace, and the responsibilization of all world problems. When I was studying film, our screenwriting professor would tell us to only write stories with happy endings and follow the Hollywood plotline. Such misfortune in the artistic world is a reflection of late-term capitalism phenomena. I used to take pride in being very flexible, but now I am aware that this flexibility is a reaction to the ever-changing climate in the labour market. Being able to reflect on many aspects of my own life has been refreshing. I will revisit this book after reading more anti-capitalist/marxist literature to gain a clearer understanding of Fisher&amp;rsquo;s references.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, an astonishingly positive experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>